<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Happy Collision</title><description>The mostly technical musings of Don Denton.</description><link>https://happycollision.com/</link><item><title>The Shoemaker&apos;s Children Go Barefoot</title><link>https://happycollision.com/2014/01/12/the-shoemakers-children-go-barefoot/</link><guid>https://happycollision.com/2014/01/12/the-shoemakers-children-go-barefoot/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I believe that is how the saying goes. Rather than wait to start posting the content I have had in mind, I think now is the best time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had a “Ready, set, go” mindset—as many of us do—for the better part of my adult life. Unfortunately, that mindset tends to lead to procrastination. Maybe not for all of us, but for many. Certainly for me. Time to switch to “Go, set, ready” instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is an example of that very switch. It is a place for me to connect to the world of technology and software development. Web development work is one of the things that I do, though you might not know it from the look of this site. At the time of this writing, happycollision.com is using the Twenty Thirteen theme right out of the box from WordPress. No need for me to spend time creating some special theme or entire CMS for this site. I have other things to do and other clients to satisfy. But for the first time, I am not going to let my lack of readiness stop me from creating content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you get down to it, Content is King, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Vagrantfile that creates and populates MySQL database</title><link>https://happycollision.com/2014/01/17/vagrantfile-that-creates-and-populates-MYSQL-database/</link><guid>https://happycollision.com/2014/01/17/vagrantfile-that-creates-and-populates-MYSQL-database/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I started poking around a &lt;a href=&quot;http://discourse.org&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;/a&gt; install. I was a bit hesitant to start learning a whole new language (Ruby) on the chance that I could find a good use for Discourse in my work. I found a one, but it will be a while before I’ll actually implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was fumbling around the installation guide, it slowly dawned on me that this &lt;a href=&quot;http://vagrantup.com&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; thing I was using via their instruction is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, Vagrant is a fantastic piece of software that allows you “create and configure lightweight, reproducible, and portable development environments.” Basically, you can spin up a server with one command and have all your dev files sitting in a folder that is already mounted to the VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually solves a little problem I’ve had. Tons of my older work depends on MySQL databases to run at all, so when I need to test something or work on a new feature, I tend toward &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bnj.com/blog/cowboy-coding-pink-sombrero/&quot;&gt;cowboy coding&lt;/a&gt;. It’s bitten me a couple times, but the &lt;em&gt;thought&lt;/em&gt; of installing MAMP (or installing MySQL on my Mac) and configuring MySQL just because I need a running database to work on a little bit of php…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am using Vagrant, so it’s a little easier. But the big relief comes with the little script I wrote that I embed in the Vagrantfile. It looks for a file with the extension &lt;code&gt;.sql&lt;/code&gt; and creates a database and user in MySQL with the name of the file. So if your file is &lt;code&gt;webapp.sql&lt;/code&gt; then the script creates a database called &lt;code&gt;webapp&lt;/code&gt; and a user by the same name with “pass” as their password. Then, it &lt;em&gt;loads the sql into the database&lt;/em&gt;. Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now whenever I need to whip up a quick little feature for an old project, I put this Vagrantfile in the root directory of the application along with the last MySQL backup file I made, type &lt;code&gt;vagrant up&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal, grab a drink and start working. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/happycollision/8469423&quot;&gt;Here’s the script&lt;/a&gt;. I hope it is useful for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>//The Importance of Comments</title><link>https://happycollision.com/2014/03/22/the-importance-of-comments/</link><guid>https://happycollision.com/2014/03/22/the-importance-of-comments/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Much of my coding time these days is spent working on projects that are not completely mine. This is a change from years past when all my code was controlled by me. I would create websites and tools to manage those sites—mostly right on top of Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a day job that also involves a heavy amount of coding, most of my time is spent on code that has &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with my personal or contract work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that my head is full of things like Ember.js and Grunt (with a touch of ASP), I find that my original work for myself and my personal clients is looking very foreign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my newest goal is not to go over all the old stuff and comment the heck out of it, but to &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; comment as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to welcome me from the depths (well, maybe not the &lt;em&gt;depths&lt;/em&gt;) of arrogance and stupidity to the world where normal people live.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Heartbleed: your passwords are public now</title><link>https://happycollision.com/2014/04/09/heartbleed-your-passwords-are-public-now/</link><guid>https://happycollision.com/2014/04/09/heartbleed-your-passwords-are-public-now/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I am not going to waste your time here. If you want to know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what Heartbleed is, there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=what%20is%20heartbleed&quot;&gt;plenty of sites&lt;/a&gt; that will give you that. This will all be in layman’s terms and will be far from precise, but will be accurate enough for normal people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Heartbleed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heartbleed, made public on April 7, is the nickname for a problem with some of the code that keeps the internet safe. It actually made sites that were supposed to be super secure &lt;em&gt;worse&lt;/em&gt; than sites that were unsecured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has never been a vulnerability that affected this much of the internet before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heartbleed has nothing to do with your computer. It has to do with websites &lt;em&gt;and services&lt;/em&gt; you use. The number of people who use the internet and have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; been affected by Heartbleed is, essentially, zero. Don’t brush this off: you are not insulated from this, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://heartbleed.com&quot;&gt;Heartbleed.com&lt;/a&gt;, emphasis mine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have tested some of our own services from attacker’s perspective. We attacked ourselves from outside, without leaving a trace. &lt;strong&gt;Without using any privileged information or credentials&lt;/strong&gt; we were able steal from ourselves the secret keys used for our X.509 certificates, &lt;strong&gt;user names&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;passwords&lt;/strong&gt;, instant messages, &lt;strong&gt;emails&lt;/strong&gt; and business critical documents and communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do I have to do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No matter who you are&lt;/strong&gt;, you need to get ready to change your passwords. Period. If you are the type of person who uses the same password for multiple websites or services (Gmail, Yahoo Mail, etc.), you are &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; vulnerable. I’m sorry, but it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the tricky part: &lt;strong&gt;You have to wait until the websites you use are no longer vulnerable&lt;/strong&gt;. The sites affected need fix the problem on their end before you can do anything on your end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest thing you can do now is wait until the weekend and then change all your passwords. Any service that is worth their salt will have patched the leak by then. Not the safest route, but doable for people who don’t have time to be concerned. UNIQUE PASSWORDS, please. This is a great time to make sure you don’t use the same password for your bank account as you use anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be safe, check the sites you have passwords on with &lt;a href=&quot;http://filippo.io/Heartbleed/&quot;&gt;this tool&lt;/a&gt;. If they pass the test, go ahead and change your password there. I cannot stress enough how important it is to make the password unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How am I supposed to remember unique passwords for all my sites?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth your while to find a system that works. However you need to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend either &lt;a href=&quot;http://lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt;. I use the latter. LastPass was, technically, compromised but they claim that the compromise didn’t allow attackers to get any data. 1Password was only compromised if you use a specific part of their service, which I do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both these services are helpful when changing passwords as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This seems like kind of a pain in the rear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep. But to paraphrase Zig Ziglar, “You only have to floss the teeth you want to keep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be safe out there, folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think I have gotten something wrong, please &lt;a href=&quot;http://happycollision.com/contact&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;, and I will be happy to correct.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Why I am letting go of my trademark</title><link>https://happycollision.com/2021/11/21/letting-go-of-my-trademark/</link><guid>https://happycollision.com/2021/11/21/letting-go-of-my-trademark/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;For years now, I have maintained &lt;a href=&quot;https://tsdr.uspto.gov/#caseNumber=85583560&amp;amp;caseSearchType=US_APPLICATION&amp;amp;caseType=SERIAL_NO&amp;amp;searchType=statusSearch&quot;&gt;a trademark for the name Happy Collision ®&lt;/a&gt;. This was done not out of an actual need or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.likelihoodofconfusion.com/why-i-let-my-trademark-registration-lapse/&quot;&gt;out of vanity&lt;/a&gt;, but out of fear that this name would somehow be stolen out from underneath me. At this point, it sure does not seem like a good use of my money, time, and attention. (I sure wish I had realized that back then that I wouldn’t need the registration: paying the fees to the government and the lawyer I hired was no small thing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt that I’ll have any cause to fight with someone over the use of the name, despite allowing the registration with the USPTO to lapse. We shall see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, any clients I attain or currently work with will continue to communicate with me via my @happycollision email address and will continue to see the Happy Collision name and logo on any invoices they might require.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>